San Francisco and Berkeley, CA | juliens [at] berkeley.edu

I am pursuing a career in medicine to become a physician and researcher who provides care for and improves the health of communities, especially for marginalized and underserved populations.

## **EDUCATION**

2017.09 - 2021.03 UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SAN DIEGO [CUM LAUDE]

**Biochemistry and Cell Biology B.S.** 

Rady School of Management - Business Minor

SKILLS

Clinical Providing physician support in both community health and private practice clinics.

Patient education and relaying essential information to providers.

Preparing and assisting during surgical procedures.

Science Clinical Data, Industry applications, Molecular Biology, Biochemistry, and Physiology.

Experience associating with a lab and conducting research in a BSL-2 Lab Environment.

Knowledge in cell cultures, isolating compounds, and PCR techniques.

Computers Experience working with computer scientists for ML pipeline and biological analysis.

Software including Spotfire, Microsoft Office, Carestream Imaging, and Adobe CC.

Experience using R, Python, and SQL for data analysis and presentation.

Hobbies Sailing for the UC San Diego Sailing Team.

Bike building, singing in choir, and photography.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

2022.11 Nature Scientific Reports

Discovery of SARS-CoV-2 Antiviral Synergy between Remdesivir and Approved

Drugs in Human Lung Cells

https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-022-21034-5

2021.06 ACS Infectious Diseases

Screening a Library of FDA-Approved and Bioactive Compounds for Antiviral Activity

against SARS-CoV-2

https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsinfecdis.1c00017

## **EXPERIENCE**

## 2021.05 - PRESENT BAY AREA COSMETIC DERMATOLOGY - SAN FRANCISCO, CA

**Medical Assistant** 

- Explaining treatment plans, medications, and procedures to patients.
- Assisting providers in preparing for and performing dermatology procedures.
- Ability to manage timely patient flow and lead a team of assistants.

## 2021.04 - PRESENT CLINIC BY THE BAY - SAN FRANCISCO, CA

**Medical Scribe and Food Pharmacy Volunteer** 

- Working alongside physicians to provide free and patient focused medical care to uninsured and marginalized adults within the San Francisco community.
- Involved in training new scribes and developing a clinic handbook.
- Providing free and fresh produce for clinic patients to combat food insecurity.

#### 2019.07 - PRESENT

# CENTER FOR EMERGING AND NEGLECTED DISEASES – UC BERKELEY, CA CEND Intern

- Currently researching the access and distribution of life-saving COVID-19 therapeutics across the US to patients with critical need.
- Co-author on multiple COVID-19 related papers.
- Developing and implementing a small-molecule high throughput screening lab.
- Experience working with Tecan, CyBio, and EnVision equipment for screening.
- Exposure to administrative roles and negotiations with collaborating PIs to successfully begin and continue projects.

### 2020.06 - 2020.09

## BRISTOL MYERS SQUIBB - LAWRENCEVILLE, NJ

**Translational Medicine Intern** 

- Oncology biomarker research on clinical trial patient samples.
- Collaborated with a Computer Science intern to employ machine learning algorithms to optimize and comprehend biomarker discovery results.
- Integrating data science and biology for large sample screens.
- Knowledge of different screening instruments and assays for TM research.

## 2020.01 - 2020.06

# UC SAN DIEGO DIVISION OF BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES – LA JOLLA, CA

**Upper Division Biology Instructional Assistant / Tutor** 

- 2nd-time Instructional Assistant for Upper Division Biology courses.
- Led weekly hour-long discussion sections and office hours to develop student understanding of critical concepts in molecular biology and biochemistry.
- Collaboration and communication with the professor and Instructional Assistants to prepare course material and promote an effective learning environment.

#### 2018.12 - 2019.06

# SIO CENTER FOR MARINE BIOTECHNOLOGY AND BIOMEDICINE - LA JOLLA

Fenical Lab Research Intern

- Researched and worked on isolating and purifying therapeutic natural products.
- Presented projects and findings to Lab Manager, Post Docs, and PI.
- Collected and analyzed data to extrapolate bioactive compound structures.
- Experience working with HPLC and LCMS to isolate and identify molecules.

#### 2018.12 - 2019.06

## LA JOLLA SCRIPPS MEMORIAL HOSPITAL – LA JOLLA, CA

Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit Volunteer

- Assisted with pre- and post-operative patient care in an acute hospital setting.
- Restocked and prepared rooms for incoming patients.
- Transported medical materials including large volumes of blood and medications.